Guide to the Letters to William Toynbee
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Letters to William Toynbee
1870-1936
GEN MSS 299
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.6
(2 boxes)
113 letters to William Toynbee from such correspondents as Helen Paterson Allingham, Edward Montagu Butler, Lewis Harcourt, Frederic Harrison, Alfred Milner, Elizabeth Robins, and Anne Douglas Sedgwick. There also two letters written by others to others about William Toynbee.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn, 1951.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
113 letters to William Toynbee from such correspondents as Helen Paterson Allingham, Edward Montagu Butler, Lewis Harcourt, Frederic Harrison, Alfred Milner, Elizabeth Robins, and Anne Douglas Sedgwick. There also two letters written by others to others about William Toynbee.
Allingham, Helen Paterson, 1848-1926; Butler, Edward Montagu; Harcourt, Lewis Harcourt, Viscount, 1863-1922; Harrison, Frederic, 1831-1923; Milner, Alfred Milner, Viscount, 1854-1925; Robins, Elizabeth, 1862-1952; Sedgwick, Anne Douglas, 1873-1935; Toynbee, William, 1849-
- Correspondence, Series I
  - LETTERS TO WILLIAM TOYNBEE
    - A., H. ALS, 1909 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allingham, Helen Paterson. 2 ALS, Hampstead, [1904] Sep (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Scope and Contents
      Accompanied by calling card, with note on verso
    - Ashbourne, Edward Gibson. ALS, [London], 1907 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - [Barry, Alfred?] ALS, Cornwall, 1902 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Baumann, Arthur Anthony. ALS, London, 1918 Sep 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Baynes, Christopher William. ALS, [London], 1918 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Berlyn, Alfred. TLS, Covent Garden, 1912 Oct 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Blackwood, George William. ALS, Edinburgh, 1903 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Boucicault, Dion G. ALS and TLS, [London?], 1900, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Boucicault, Nina. ALS, Wyndham's Theatre, 1907 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Buckle, George Earle. 2 ALS, Chelsea, 1914, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Butler, Edward Montagu. 9 ALS, Harrow on the Hill, 1917-18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Butler, Henry Montagu. ALS, Harrow, 1880 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Calvert, Leonard?] ALS, London, n.y. Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Chappell, Henry. ALS, Bath, 1914 Aug 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Clarendon, George Herbert Hyde Villiers. TLS, [London], 1925 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Clarke, Ernest. ALS, London, 1916 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Colmache?, L] ALS, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Cotton, Henry John Stedman. ALS, [London?], 1903 Jan 7 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dawson, George. ALS, London, 1904 Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - du Maurier, Mrs. E. ALS, London, 1902 Dec 30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Du Pontet, Clement Adolphe Auguste. ALS, Harrow School, 1917 Feb 27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Frampton, George James. 2 ALS, St. John's Wood, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Goreth, T. C. ALS, 1903 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Guthrie, Thomas Anstey. ALS, [London], 1902 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Hailsham, Douglas McGarel Hogg. TLS, [London], 1936 Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hall, Sydney Prior. ALS, Haverstock Hill, 1902 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Harcourt, Lewis. 2 TLS, [London], 1904 Jul (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Harrison, Frederic. 3 ALS, Hawkhurst, 1911-12 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hawkins, Inga. 2 ALS, London, 1904 Jun (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Hayes, Edwin. ALS, Bayswater, 1903 Jan 12 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hearn, Walter Risley. ALS, Kensington Court, 1922 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Hervey, Arthur. ALS, Hyde Park, W., 1904 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Holland, Sydney. ALS, Royston, Herts, 1913 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Jackson, T. W. ALS, Oxford, 1903 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, Arthur Henry. ALS, Oxford, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Kilbracken, Arthur Godley. ALS, Tunbridge Wells, 1927 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Knollys, Edward George William Tyrwhitt. 2 TLS, Sandringham, Norfolk, 1908 Dec (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Knutsford, Arthur Henry Holland-Hibbert. ALS, London, 1918 Feb 12 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - La Panouse, vicomtesse de. ALS, London, 1915 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Linton, Elizabeth Lynn. ALS, Malvern, 1897 Dec 27 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Lister, William Tindall. TLS, [London], 1929 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Lyall, Charles James. ALS, Cornwall Gardens, 1903 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - McCormick, Constance. ALS, Berkeley Square, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Macready, Cecil Frederick Nevil. ALS, Fontainebleau, n.y. May 8 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Marquand, P[?] ALS, Bayswater, 1904 Jun 27 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Maxwell, Herbert Eustace. ALS, [Edinburgh], 1903 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Milne, ? ALS, Cambridge, 1907 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Milner, Alfred. 4 ALS, [London], 1894-1921 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Nettleship, Edward. ALS, Shottermill, Haslemere, 1903 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Nettleship, John Trivett. 2 ALS, [London], 1890, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - O'Malley, Ellen. 3 ALS, [London], 1904 Dec (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Ormsby-Gore, William George Arthur. TLS, Westminster, 1935 Mar 6 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Palmer, Arnold. ALS, Newmarket, 1927 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Parsons, Alfred. 2 ALS, Kensington, U.S.M.S. "St. Louis", 1902 Dec (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Peel, George. ALS, [London], 1920 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Perceval, C. M. ALS, Woking, 1907 Apr 12 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Rapell, George. ALS, [London], 1917 Dec 17 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Robins, Elizabeth. 2 ALS, [London?], St. James Theatre (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Roseberry, Albert Edward Harry Meyer Archibald Primrose. TL, Edinburgh, 1921 Sep 20 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Sedgwick, Anne Douglas. 4 ALS, various places, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Shadwell, Charles Lancelot. ALS, London, [1904 Dec 24] (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Sichel, Edith Helen. ALS, Hambledon Hurst, Godalming, Surrey, n.y. Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Smith, Charles Percy. ALS, [London], 1912 Nov 8 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Somerset, C. W. ALS, Avenue Theatre, n.y. Dec 24 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Steel, S. H. 2 ALS, 1907-08 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Steer, Janette. ALS, [London], n.y. May 17 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Teipiel, G. F. de. 2 ALS, Chichester, 1888-89 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Thompson, Gertrude. ALS, Petersfield, n.y. Jul 11 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Trevelyan, George Macauley. ALS, Berkhamsted, 1922 Jul 18 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Vanity Fair editor. ALS, London, 1882 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Whiteing, Richard. ALS, Bloomsbury, 1899 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Wilson, Guy Douglas Arthur Fleetwood. ALS, [London], 1922 Jul 5 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Winnington-Ingram, Arthur Foley. ALS, Fulham Palace, [1870?] Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Wood, Joseph. 2 ALS, Harrow, 1903 Nov (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Woodward, Henry. 2 ALS, London, 1903 May (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Zetland, Lawrence John Lumley Dundas. ALS, Hill Cottage, Newmarket, 1929 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - 4 ALS from unidentified correspondents, 1907-16, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    - Monson, Edmund John. ALS to the president of the Royal Indian College of Engineering [Sir George Chesney] about William Toynbee, [London], 1878 Jul 15 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Wyndham, Charles. TNS to Theyre Smith, [London], 1901, Jun 12 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      The note concerns a play of William Toynbee